Finding Aid for Martha Cook Building (University of Michigan) publications, 1916-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Martha Cook Building (University of Michigan) publications 1916-2013
Martha Cook Building (University of Michigan).
1.5 linear foot
0514 Bimu F17 2
Women's dormitory at the University of Michigan Publications include annuals, histories, newsletters, and programs. Also contains material relating to the fiftieth anniversary celebration and to the Martha Cook Alumnae Association of Detroit.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (Donor no. 5887 ) has been donated by the Board of Governors of the Martha Cook Building in several accessions.
Periodic additions to the publications expected.
The publications are open without restriction.
Please consult the history found in the finding for Martha Cook Building (University of Michigan) Records.
The Martha Cook Building Publications (40 folders) include annuals, histories, newsletters, and programs as well as material relating to the fiftieth anniversary celebration and to the Martha Cook Alumnae Association of Detroit The Publications are organized into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.; Martha Cook Building (University of Michigan)
Genre Terms:
Student publications.; Annuals.; Histories.; Newsletters.; Programs.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains a long run of Martha Cook annuals, which include photographs of the residents and descriptions of the activities taking place in the residence hall. These annual yearbooks cover the period from 1916 to1941, 1975/76, and 2000/01. There are histories, including the memoirs of Olive Chernow, who was a resident at Martha Cook when she was a student and later served as director of Martha Cook Building from 1973 to 1979. This series also contains a brief run of the newsletter The Cookie Press.
  - Annuals
    - The Cook Book, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Martha Cook Annual, 1917-1939, 2000-2009, 32 folders (Box 1)
    - Life and Times in Martha Cook Building, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Martha Cook Annual: A Panorama of Life at Martha Cook, 1940 (Box 1)
    - The Martha Cook Building, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Articles about Martha Cook, 1973-1975 and undated (Box 1)
  - Constitutions
    - Constitution, By-laws and Regulations of the Martha Cook Building, 1925-1932 (Box 1)
  - Flyers, Undated (Box 1)
  - Histories
    - The Martha Cook Building by Wystan Stevens, 1976 (Box 1)
    - The Martha Cook Building: Its History and Traditions by Elaine Macklin and Tenney Chamberlain, 1970 (Box 1)
    - My Years at the Martha Cook Building by Olive Chernow (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - The Cookie Press, 1946-1947, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Alumnae Associaton, 1993-2013, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Other
    - Martha's Cookin', 1980 (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - Vesper Service, 1929-1934 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications include publications describing the Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration and the activities of the Martha Cook Alumnae Association of Detroit.
  - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration
    - Histories
      - The Martha Cook Building: Fiftieth Anniversary,1915-1965, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Programs (Box 1)
  - Martha Cook Alumnae Association of Detroit
    - Christmas Breakfast or Brunch
      - Invitations, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
    - Scholarship Luncheon and Tea
      - Invitations, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
      - Programs, 1966-1978 (Box 1)